好啦我会很快的
All right, I'll make it super fast.
哈喽哇我是Destin，字幕翻译给虫，欢迎观看Smarter Every Day节目
It's me, Destin. Welcome back to SmarterEveryDay.
当你坐飞机，遇到客舱失压，顶板会自动掉下来氧气面罩
When you're in a jet, if the cabin depressurizes, they drop this little mask out of the top.
当你在FL150(4500米)高空失压客舱内摘下面罩会发生什么呢？
What happens if you're in a depressurized cabin and you're up above 15,000 feet [4,500m] and you drop your mask?
你会缺氧，而你需要立即采取措施
Something called hypoxia takes effect and you got to do something about that.
让我们开始今天的节目吧
Let's get smarter every day.
坐飞机前你们肯定听空乘说过
You've heard the flight attendants say this before,
“先给自己戴面罩，再帮别人戴上”。但这是为什么？
“Secure your own mask before helping others.” But why?
为什么会这样呢？我先给身边孩子戴上面罩花的三十秒就那么重要吗？
Why did they say that? Is the 30 seconds it takes to put on a kid’s mask next to me really that important?
15年前我参加NASA约翰逊太空中心的一个微重力学生飞行项目时我明白了原因
15 years ago I learned the answer to this question when I was selected to participate
in NASA’s Reduced Gravity Student Flight Opportunities Program at NASA’s Johnson Space Center.
当时在上失重飞机（当时那架飞机绰号“呕吐彗星”）之前
Before I got to ride in the Vomit Comet I had to
要现在NBL的低氧舱进行一些生理上的训练
Neutral Buoyancy Lab, NBL: NASA的中性浮力实验室，在休斯敦约翰逊太空中心旁边
航天员的太空行走任务就是在这的中性浮力水池中训练的
undergo physiological training in a hypobaric chamber at the Neutral Buoyancy Lab.
回到现在，今天，航天员Don Pettit打算更新下他的缺氧训练资质
Fast forward to now. Today, astronaut Don Pettit is scheduled to renew his hypoxia training certification
我问能不能跟他一起去
and I asked him if it would be okay if I tagged along.
然后他和我去隔壁低氧舱训练前一起在国际空间站训练用的水池里先游了几圈
He let me swim a few laps with him over the International Space Station mock-up in
the Neutral Buoyancy Lab before we headed over next door for Don’s training.
——你看着像让狗拽上来的一样  ——我感觉也是
– You look like something the dog dragged in. – I feel like it, too.
缺氧训练的目的在于让航天员、飞行员准确了解
The purpose of hypoxia training is to let astronauts and aviators know when their brain’s
他们的大脑何时停止工作，这点非常重要
about to stop working correctly, which is very, very important.
你坐飞机在高空时，虽然外面空气稀薄，但客舱内是加压过的
If you’re at a high altitude in an airplane, the air is thinner but the cabin is pressurized,
所以你身体不会缺氧
so your body gets enough oxygen to operate.
为了模拟客舱失压，NASA把航天员放在一个密封舱内
To simulate cabin depressurization, NASA puts its astronauts in a chamber at sea level
然后一点点抽掉里面的空气，来模拟高空的低压
and then pumps the air out to thin it out, so that it simulates a higher altitude.
Don的训练前还是要学习一个
Don’s training starts with class work focused on understanding the specific
身体在缺氧时的特别现象与症状
signs and symptoms of hypoxia in his own body.
而训练的目的也是让你了解你自身的生理症状从而快速作出应对
The goal of this training is to understand your own physiological symptoms so that you can take action quickly.
比如，Don说他缺氧时视野会变小，会感觉气饥饿（就是憋得慌）
For example, Don said he experiences tunnel vision and air hunger,
但我记得我15年前的训练我的症状是欣快与耳鸣
but I remember for my training 15 years ago that get really happy and start to tingle all over.
——我现在实在严肃不起来因为我现在是这个德行
– I can't take you seriously because this is what you look like.
——啥德行？我看着多正常多严肃233
– What? What do you mean? I look perfectly normal.
这是我们接下来要做的实验
This is the experiment we're going to do:
Don和我一起进低氧舱，然后氧气含量降低到FL250的高度
Don and I are both going to enter the hypobaric chamber at the same time and fly to FL250,
然后我们一起摘掉面罩，感受缺氧带来的影响
at which point we are going to remove our masks and start to experience the effects of hypoxia.
Don是对照组，因为他是受过训练的航天员，所以自身能感知缺氧症状并马上采取措施
Don is the control. He’s a trained astronaut who recognizes the symptoms for hypoxia and immediately corrects for them.
而我，作为实验组，在NASA航空医生的严密监督下
I, on the other hand, am under the direct supervision of a NASA flight surgeon and
我请求在感知到缺氧后能否延迟一分钟再戴面具，从而让我更了解
after I notice the effects of hypoxia,
I’ve asked if I could delay for about one minute so we can better understand
缺氧后不马上戴面罩的生理现象
the physiological effects of not immediately putting your mask on.
好啦我们进密封舱了，准备一下吧
OK, here we go, we're getting set up.
Jerry帮我弄这些设备的时候，我先介绍一下两种失压的情况
While Jerry gets me situated, I’m going to talk about the two types of decompression:
第一种是紧急失压，就像呆在要炸的气球里一样
Number one, rapid decompression this is like being inside of an explosion.
突然间气压降低，空气里的水蒸气会液化成雾
You dump all your pressure instantly, all the moisture condenses out of the air,
一瞬间就像在云中，非常吓人，非常暴力（不像我）
you’re suddenly in a cloud. Very scary, very violent.
厉害吧，所以咱们不玩这个。我们要模拟的是缓慢失压
Yeah, we’re not going to do that. What we're going to do is simulate a slow, steady leak.
最开始是大气压强，然后每分钟上升5000英尺(1500米)
We’re going to start at sea level and ascend at 5,000 feet [1,500m] per minute
一直上升到25000英尺(7500米)，用飞行员的话说，叫FL250高度
all the way up to 25,000 feet [7,500m], or as aviators call it, flight level 250.
OK,我还要多说一句，我们这个演示是在25000英尺(7500米)高度进行的
OK, I want to make one thing abundantly clear. We performed this demonstration at 25,000 feet [7,500m].
我当时意识保持了大概三到五分钟
I had about three to five minutes of consciousness left.
然而大多数航班飞行高度在35000英尺(10000米)，看这个表，那个高度氧气少得多得多
However, most airliners travel at 35,000 feet [10,000m]. Look at this chart: There is way less oxygen up there.
在35000英尺(10000米)，你的意识几乎只剩几秒
At 35,000 feet [10,000m] you literally have seconds of useful consciousness at that altitude.
几秒内你就会从一个正常人，变成一个无助到
You can go from a normally rational person to someone so helpless you can
连自己的命都救不了的人了
even save yourself if your life depends on it.
我不……我……我不想死
I don’t- I don’t wanna die
我不是为了吓唬你，我只是想让你明白
I don’t tell you this to scare you. I simply want you to understand the
飞机上的安全卡片，和飞行前安全演示中的生理学
physiology behind that little preflight announcement.
“先给自己戴面罩，再帮别人”
“Put your mask on first before helping others.”
呃……我也不想讲太多生理上的东西
Look, I don’t want to get too deep or philosophical with this,
但我想说这里还有个好玩的事
but I think there's a neat metaphor here.
有时对一个人来说看到别人身上的问题
Sometimes it’s easy for me to see the problems in other people and focus on that
然后全力解决很容易，但却忘了自己也有问题
and I get so carried away with fixing other people that I forget that I have a problem too.
所以说这个演示真的非常有意思
And I think that’s what’s so cool about this demonstration.
有时你只要先把你自己面罩戴上，先管好你自己
Sometimes you just got to put your mask on first and get yourself sorted
然后再管别人
before you can help others.
——还是要再次谢谢您救我一命  ——不客气啦，这一直是我的荣幸
– So thanks again for saving my life, by the way. – You're welcome, it was an honor and a pleasure.
——刚刚太棒了，谢谢啦
– It was great. – All the time. –Thank you.
好啦，我们学会了为什么要先给自己戴氧气面罩
There you go, now we learned why you need to put your mask on first
然后再帮助别人。你肯定不想缺氧的
before you help other people. You don’t want to get hypoxia.
我是Destin，字幕翻译给虫，祝你们每天都变得更聪明！
I'm Destin, you’re getting smarter every day, have a good one.
喜欢请点赞、投币、收藏、分享、关注一波
If you feel like this video earned your subscription, feel free to click this box
原YouTuber也有自己的Patreon，喜欢可以去赞助
that I’m in right now or you can click the support on patreon and you'll be
这样每次他更新的时候就会有邮件提醒
notified via email every time I release a video.
感谢大家观看，也要感谢NASA的NBL的一群牛人
I want to say thank you to the awesome people at NASA’s neutral buoyancy laboratory.
他们保证了我的安全，在他们身边让我每时每刻都在提高致己的姿势水平
They kept me super safe, super informed and they educated me and made me smarter every moment I was with them.
真的太厉害了。感谢大家
That was really awesome. Thank you so much, guys.
总之，我是Destin，字幕翻译给虫，祝你们每天都变得更聪明！
Anyway, I’m Destin, you’re getting smarter every day. Have a good one.
——Don, 这是什么？  ——我把泳镜上镜片弄下来
–What’s the deal here, Don? – Well I cut the regular lens off of the goggles
——嗯  ——然后把我的旧眼镜镜片切好
–OK – and then I took an old pair of glasses and I cut the plastic to fit my
——让它能适配这泳镜，然后粘上  ——所以你私人订制了一个泳镜，这样水下就能看清了
goggles and then I glued them on. – You basically MacGyvered your own goggles, so that you had correction underwater.
——没错  ——厉害了
– That’s right. – That’s pretty good.